And welcome now to the code for our user interface, which we will find in this Python module.
사용자 인터페이스에 대한 코드에 오신 것을 환영합니다 파이썬 을 살펴보도록 하죠
Price is right dot pi.
가격 이즈 라이트 닷파이예요
And this is where we will be looking at particularly the code that constructs the UI behind our product.
여기서 특히 제품 뒤 UI를 구성하는 코드를 살펴볼 거예요
And it starts with a few imports.
몇 가지 수입품으로 시작하죠
This very important one to import Gradio.
그라디오를 수입하는 데 아주 중요한 부분이죠
And this even more important one to import the deal agent framework, which is at the heart of what
이건 훨씬 더 중요한 겁니다 거래 에이전트 프레임워크를 수입하는 데요 우리가 구축한 것의
we built.
핵심이죠
Uh, and then it defines a class app.
클래스 앱을 정의하죠
And if I scroll to the bottom, you'll see that at the bottom it calls app dot run.
아래로 스크롤을 하면 app.lan이라고 호출하는 것이 보이죠.
It creates app and then runs it.
앱을 생성해 실행하죠
And what does that involve creating?
뭘 만드는 거죠?
It does very little.
별로 하는 게 없어요
It just sets an empty variable for agent framework.
에이전트 프레임워크를 위한 빈 변수를 설정하죠
The juice the meat is in the run uh method.
육즙이 흘러나오는 방식이죠
And that of course creates a user interface using Gradio more advanced construct of great blocks with
사용자 인터페이스를 생성하죠 그래디오의 더 고급 구성 요소를 이용해서요 가격은 적당하다를
the Price is Right.
통해서요
Um, and then what you see here is some code that's quite similar to the code that we've already looked
여기 보이는 코드는 우리가 이미 봤던 것과 꽤 유사해요
In fact, the user interface part of it right here is identical.
사실 사용자 인터페이스는 여기 이 부분과 동일해요
We have some rows with some titles.
말다툼이 좀 있었어요
Um, and then we include our data frame.
그리고 데이터 프레임을 포함해요
It has description price estimate discount and Earl as the columns.
설명 가격 추정 할인이랑 얼이 기둥이에요
And it's set up and assigned to something called opportunities data frame just as before.
아까처럼 기회 데이터 프레임이란 것에 설정되고 할당되죠
Uh, the only thing that's changed is what's coming right afterwards.
바뀐 건 그 후에 일어날 일뿐이에요
So here we go.
자, 시작하죠
This is the new stuff in this file.
이 파일의 새로운 것들이죠
There is, uh, a UI dot load.
UI .load가 있어요
So this is again where we tell Gradio.
여기서 다시 그래디오에게 말하죠
When you load, we want you to carry out a particular, uh, instruction.
장전할 때 특정 지시를 따라야 해요
And we specify that using the standard format for gradio, where you start with the name of the function,
그러데이션을 위한 표준 포맷을 이용해 명시합니다 함수의 이름으로 시작하면
it should call the inputs and the outputs.
입력과 출력을 호출해야 하죠
And in this case we're saying we want you to call the function called start.
이 경우엔 start라는 함수를 호출하라고 하고 있어요
There are no inputs to this function.
이 함수에 입력값이 없어요
And whatever it returns, we want you to hook that up to the opportunities data frame.
그게 뭘 반환하든 그걸 기회 데이터 프레임에 연결하세요
And that means we expect it to return some information that is suitable to be put into a table.
그 말은 테이블에 Put이 가능한 일부 정보를 반환하길 기대한다는 거죠
So that's what we expect to see from a function start.
함수 시작에서 기대하는 게 바로 이거죠
And then we're going to create another Gradio UI component called a GR dot timer.
그런 다음 다른 Gadio UI 구성 요소를 생성합니다 GR.Timer라는 거죠
And that is something which which does some timing.
그게 타이밍을 잡아주죠
It is in fact a UI component which is invisible.
이건 사실 보이지 않는 UI 구성 요소예요
It's something that runs behind the scenes and it will wake up every 60s.
무대 뒤에서 돌아가며 60대마다 깨어나는 거죠
And what does it do every 60s well, you have to tell Gradio what it should do.
60년대에는 어떻게∙∙∙ 아니, 그래디오에게 어떻게 해야 할지 말해줘야 해요
And the way you tell Gradio is by calling timer, dot, tick.
당신은 그래디오에게 타이머, 점, 체크라고 말해요
And when you do that, you provide the information to Gradio again using the standard Gradio structure
그렇게 할 때 정보를 다시 그라디오에게 제공하죠 표준 그라디오 구조의 표준 접근법을
standard approach.
사용해서요
You tell it the function that will be called.
호출될 함수를 알려주는 거죠
In this case I say go.
이 경우에는 출발해야죠
You give it the inputs, there aren't any and the outputs, whatever go returns should be put into the
입력값을 주는데 아무것도 없으면 출력은 무엇이든지 기회 데이터 프레임에
opportunities data frame.
놓여져야 해요
Again, simple as that.
아주 간단하죠
The select method here that's that we call is exactly the same as before.
우리가 호출하는 SELECT 메서드는 아까와 완전히 똑같아요
It's another thing that hasn't changed.
변하지 않은 또 다른 거죠
It's not exactly the same.
완전히 똑같진 않아요
It's changed a tiny bit, but it's basically the same.
비트만 좀 바뀌었지 거의 똑같아요
And it ends with a call to the agent framework planner messenger alert, alert about the opportunity.
에이전트 프레임워크 플래너에게 전화하는 걸로 끝나요 메신저 알림 기회에 대한 알림이죠
So you probably noticed the small the small change there.
작은 변화가 보이실 거예요
It's going to do a full alert.
전체 알림을 할 거예요
Uh, and all that remains is for us to go and look at the two functions we're expecting to see start
이제 남은 건 시작과 시작을 볼 수 있는 두 가지 함수를 살펴보는 거예요
And at the top of the display you will find is indeed start and go the two functions in question.
디스플레이 상단에 시작과 두 가지 함수가 있어요
And if we look at them, let's start with start.
그럼 시작부터 살펴보죠
What start does is it creates a new instance of the deal agent framework.
시작은 거래 에이전트 프레임워크의 새 인스턴스를 생성해요
The key object that controls our whole framework.
전체 프레임워크를 통제하는 핵심 객체죠
It instantiates it, and it then asks it for its memory of what opportunities does it have.
인스턴스화하고 어떤 기회가 있는지 메모리를 요청하죠
And then it calls this function table for with these opportunities and it returns that table.
그리고 이 기회들을 위해 함수 테이블을 호출하고 그 테이블을 반환하죠
So what does table four do.
4번 테이블은 뭘 하죠?
Table four is this tiny function up here.
4번 테이블은 이 작은 함수예요
So table four takes opportunities.
4번 테이블은 기회를 잡아요
And then you remember opportunities if we go in here.
여기 들어가면 기회가 있다는 걸 기억하세요
Opportunities are these objects here.
이 물건들이 기회예요
That is exactly what gets stored in the memory of the agent framework contains a deal an estimate and
에이전트 프레임워크의 메모리에 저장되는 게 바로 그겁니다 거래, 추정, 할인을 포함하죠
That is an opportunity.
그게 기회예요
So we go back to week eight.
8주 차로 돌아가 보죠
So um, the this function converts an opportunity object into just a list of strings.
이 함수는 기회 객체를 문자열 목록으로 변환해요
A list of lists of strings with the description, the price, the estimate, the discount, the URL
문자열 리스트입니다 설명, 가격, 추정, 할인 URL
exactly the type, the structure that's needed to slot into the data frame that we have down here.
정확한 유형과 구조죠 여기 아래 데이터 프레임에 넣어야 하는 거요
So again, start just simply creates a deal.
시작은 단순히 거래를 만드는 거죠
Agent framework.
프레임워크 요원이에요
Looks at its memory, converts that into strings and returns it and go.
메모리를 보고 문자열로 변환해 리턴하고 가는 거죠
Which is the thing that gets called every 60s.
60년대마다 그렇게 불리죠
Go is going to do something very, very similar.
고도 아주 비슷한 걸 할 거예요
You'll see it looks very similar.
아주 비슷하게 생겼어요
It just has this one little tiny line added, a tiny little line.
아주 작은 선 하나만 추가된 거예요
It doesn't do very much.
별 효과가 없어요
It does everything.
만능이에요
This is the line that calls run on our agent framework.
에이전트 프레임워크에서 실행되는 라인이죠
It's the thing that we were doing manually before.
전에는 수동으로 작업했었죠
It triggers the entire workflow that we have built.
우리가 구축한 워크플로우 전체를 촉발하죠
And that's what go does.
그게 고우의 역할이죠
And go will be kicked off every 60s by this GR timer so that that is the business of it.
GR 타이머로 60분마다 고가 차단됩니다 그게 작업의 핵심이죠
All that remains is to see it working in action.
이제 작동하는 걸 보는 일만 남았죠
And so now to see this happening, we're going to go to the launcher and we're going to open a new terminal.
이제 런처로 가서 새 터미널을 열어 볼게요
And I'm going to change to my to activate my conda environment with conda activate LMS.
이제 변경할 것은 LMS를 활성화한 콘다 환경을 활성화하는 거죠
There we go.
됐어요
And now I can run it by just typing Python price is right.
파이썬 + $s right이라고 입력하면 실행할 수 있어요
Dot py should be as simple as that.
도트 파이는 이렇게 간단해요
Let's see a bit of a drum roll.
드럼 비트 주세요
And 321.
321번도요
Here we go.
시작할게요
There's a pause while it thinks for a second and bam!
잠깐 생각하는 동안 멈췄다가 쾅! 하고 터져요
Up comes the price is right and there's more work going on.
가격이 적당해서 더 많은 일이 진행되고 있어요
And here we see right in front of us.
바로 우리 앞에 있어요
What we're looking at, of course, is the memory.
우리가 보는 건 물론 메모리예요
We're looking at the opportunities that it's come up with.
주어진 기회를 살피는 거죠
And we can scroll down and see this bottom item here.
스크롤을 내려 하단 항목을 볼 수 있어요
I do believe that that is the item that was just surfaced to us most recently, when we ran it from
가장 최근에야 그 물건이 떠올랐다고 생각해요 전에 명령줄에서
the command line before.
실행했을 때요
Um, and of course it then puts it into its memory.
그리고 당연히 메모리에 저장하죠
So we're seeing the items that have been surfaced here.
여기서 발견된 물건들을 보고 있어요
And if I go back over to, uh, the command line, we'll see, of course, that it initialized, it
명령줄로 다시 가보면 초기화되고 설정되고 준비된 것이 보이죠 이제
set things up, it got itself ready, uh, and it's now going to be sitting in a loop so that, uh,
반복문 안에 있게 될 겁니다 에이전트가 체크하기를
it's going to be waiting for the agent to tick.
기다리고 있죠
And after a minute, it will kick off and launch and hopefully you're doing the same thing.
1분 후에 시작될 겁니다 여러분도 그렇게 하세요
You've opened this up, you're running it, you're going to give this a try.
이걸 열어 실행하고 있으니 시도해 보세요
And like me, you will then see it run.
그럼 저처럼 달리는 걸 보게 될 거예요
And I will go to the next lecture where we will take a look at the outcome.
다음 강의에서는 그 결과를 살펴볼 거예요
Uh, I will see you there.
거기서 봐요